《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
我在地球上的时间不多了
My time on this earth is coming to an end.
你现在是不同物质的一部分
You're part of something different now.
是负力的一部分  痛苦在你脑中疾驰
Part of a negative force. Pain racing through your mind.
斯旺完全控制了她
Thawne really got to her.
她的闪电变成红色了
Her lightning. It was red.
-瑞内·艾德勒  -歇洛克·威尔斯
- Renée Adler. - Sherloque Wells.
你是超能力者
You're a meta.
你来自未来
You're from the future.
-我们能成功完成任务  -什么任务
- The mission can succeed. - What mission?
杀死所有超能力者
To kill every last meta-human.
蝉的匕首能抑制超能力
Cicada's dagger can dampen powers.
如果有什么能够摧毁那把匕首的话
If anything's gonna destroy that dagger,
就是这支镜像枪
it's this mirror gun.
蝉手中拿着致命病毒
Cicada has a lethal virus.
她偷走雾化器  这样她就可以散播病毒
She stole the atomizer so she could spread the virus.
蝉要杀死城里的所有超能力者
Cicada is gonna kill every meta-human in the city.
十五年了  斯旺
15 years, Thawne.
告诉我  濒死的滋味如何
Tell me, how's it feel to know you're about to become extinct?
我想时间会证明一切
I guess time will tell.
我会很想你的
I'm gonna miss the hell out of you.
尤其是我们的洗心革面环节
Especially our rehabilitation time.
尝尝接下来这个的滋味如何
How about a taste of what's to come?
说来嘲讽  不是吗
Ironic, isn't it?
给予你超能力的和终结你的竟是同物
The same thing that gives you your powers is gonna end you.
是时候了
It's time.
闪 电 侠
第五季
第二十一集
我们需要阻止瘟疫传播
We need to stop this plague from spreading.
我们会的
We will.
我们不止要屠杀这个城市的超能力者
We can't just purge the meta-humans in this city.
还要让他们每一个人在星球上消失得无影无踪
We need to wipe every one of them off the face of the planet.
我们会的
We will.
你得向我保证这办法能成功  格蕾西
You need to promise me this will work, Gracie.
我说了会成功的
I said it will.
到我们终结一切的时候了  格蕾西
It's time we finish this, Gracie.
是时候续写我们的传奇了
It's time to ensure our legacy.
这是我们了解到的关于制冷雾化器的信息
Here's what we know about the Cryo-atomizer.
唐豪瑟最初发明它是为了
Tannhauser originally developed it
对付由干旱造成的陆地火灾
to combat land fires caused by droughts.
因此制冷雾化器可以将冷空气颗粒分散到大气中
So the Cryo-atomizer can disperse cold air particles
从而引发降雨
into the atmosphere that triggers rainfall.
但是  如果蝉能用从西斯科这里偷走的
However, if Cicada can replace the cold particles
原型解药取代冷冻颗粒
with the cure prototypes she stole from Cisco...
原型解药能治愈的人还不如它害死的多
Which doesn't cure so much as it kills.
她就能感染整座城市
She could infect the entire city.
以及其中的每个超能力者
And every meta-human in it.
事情不妙  但所幸天无绝人之路
Not great, but this dark cloud does have a silver lining.
也就是说如果蝉已经得到了
Which is if Cicada had everything
她执行计划需要的一切
that she needs to carry out her plan...
那她早就完成任务了
would've already done so.
他说得对
He's right.
她一定是还有东西没找到  不然我们就完了
She must be missing something or else we'd be done.
没错  但我们时间不多了
Yeah, but not for long.
她会分秒必争
She's not gonna waste any time.
不管她还需要的是什么
Whatever it is that she needs,
现在她就在外面寻找着它
she's out there looking for it right now.
那我们马上行动
Well, then we move right away.
我们尽快向需要的人提供解药
We get the cure to everyone who needs it as soon as possible.
所以我们只要分发某种神奇药物就能扭转局面吗
So we just up and release some game-changing wonder drug?
我们测试过它了  它会起效的
We tested it. We know it works.
现在人们比以前任何时候都需要选择权
People need a choice now more than ever.
我们有足够多的解药吗
Do we have enough for the cure?
还不够多
Not nearly enough.
凯特琳  你制作更多解药需要多久
Caitlin, how fast can you make more?
我想我们过会儿就会知道了
Guess we'll find out.
好的  很好
Okay, okay, good.
现在我们只需找个地方分发解药
Now we just need to find someplace to distribute it.
中城警局如何
Well, what about CCPD?
它是公共场所  每个人都会觉得去那里很安全
It's public. Everybody feels safe going there.
是的  但是在一处聚集这么多超能力者
Yeah, but gathering that many metas in one place
会让他们成为很大的攻击目标  对吧
is gonna make it one big target, right?
蝉手里有病毒和雾化器
Cicada has the virus and the atomizer,
这让每一个超能力者都成为了攻击对象
that makes every meta everywhere a target.
这样如何
Well, how about this?
你们尽快制作出更多的解药
You guys make up as much of the cure as you can
我和塞西尔去和辛格谈谈
and Cecile and I will talk to Singh.
-可以  -好的
- Yeah. - All right.
我去提醒一下瑞内
I'm going to warn Renée.
去吧
Yeah.
行了  我们也去追踪蝉吧
All right, let's track Cicada too.
在我们找到她之前准备好与她交手
Get ready to face her when we find her.
我们一步一步慢慢来
Let's take it one step at a time.
跟我来
Follow me.
-那是卫星的核心吗  -是的
- Is that the satellite core? - That's right.
镜像枪上的反光板
The reflective panels on the mirror gun
不是我们从卫星上得到的唯一物件
aren't the only thing we got from the satellite.
我们还有核心和匕首
We also have the core and, of course, the dagger.
所以它们都是由完全相同的合金组成
So they're all composed of the exact same alloy
-并且含有相同的暗物质水平  -没错
- and contain the same dark matter levels? - Yup.
所以如果镜像枪对核心有效
So if the Mirror Gun works on the core,
那么它就也能对付蝉的匕首
then it should work on Cicada's dagger.
确认检验的方法只有一种
Only one way to know for sure.
或许你们可以往后退点
You might wanna step back.
我是说  你们无法想象这把枪能做什么
I mean, you don't know what this gun's gonna do.
我是说  我们不该在这么小的区域开火
I mean, we shouldn't be firing this in such a small space
但如果你不曾脱掉短裤在冰面上滑行
but what's life if you don't pull down your shorts
你就不知道什么才是人生
and slide on the icery once in a while?
那就来吧
Here we go!
会有什么事发生吗  还是说
Is something supposed to happen or...
它去哪里了
Where did it go?
这不重要
It doesn't matter.
这东西有用
This thing works.
成功了
It works!
我们终于能摧毁蝉的匕首了
We can finally destroy Cicada's dagger.
如果我们使用它  我们就有能力了
If we do that, we have our powers.
然后我们就能阻止她了
And we can stop her.
诺拉  你还好吗
N--Nora, are you okay?
很好  怎么了
Yeah, why?
诺拉  今天早上你的闪电像斯旺一样是红色的
Nora, earlier today you had red lightning like Thawne's.
我们想确认一下你的情况能否出去行动
We want to make sure you're okay to get out there.
我很好  行吗
I'm fine, okay?
凯特琳给我做了所有检查
Caitlin ran every test in the book.
我的闪电回到原来正常的颜色了
My lightning's back to its normal color.
另外  斯旺的神速力是靠负面情绪推动的
And besides, Thawne's Speed Force is fueled by negative emotions,
可我现在心情相当阳光
and right now I feel pretty dang positive.
很好  我们是你的父母  担心你是应该的
Okay. We're your parents. It's our job to worry.
唯一需要担心的应该是二代蝉
The only one that should be worrying is Cicada II.
你想要我为城里的每个超能力者
You want me to open the doors to the CCPD
敞开中城警局的大门
to every meta in this city?
大卫  这些人们需要我们的保护
David, these people need our protection.
而且并不是所有的超能力者都是罪犯
And not all metas are criminals.
他们中有一些也是医生和学生  甚至警察
You know, some of them are doctors and students and cops.
我明白  但这是警察局  不是私人诊所
I know, but this is a police station, not a clinic.
尖端科研实验室认为解药安全可行
S.T.A.R. Labs says that the cure is safe
而且像流感疫苗一样容易接种
and it's as easy to give as a flu shot.
但尖端科研实验室不是食品药品监督管理局
Well, S.T.A.R. Labs isn't exactly the FDA.
听着  我们得在这分发解药
Look, we have to do it here.
光是审批流程在医疗机构就得耗费数周时间
Red tape alone, it would take weeks at a medical facility.
如果我们什么事都不做  就会眼看
If we do nothing, there's a whole bunch of citizens
大批原本有机会获救的市民死去
who could've been saved that will die on our watch.
我不会允许这种事发生的
I'm not having that.
好吧  既然你认为这办法可行
Well, you clearly believe in this.
那我也同意施行
So I'm willing to as well.
但这意味着会有一大堆政府报告要做
But that means there's going to be a lot of political navigating.
所以我一早会去市政厅汇报情况
So I'll go down to city hall and brief them in the morning.
我走了以后  你全权负责
While I'm away, you're in charge.
新信息
歇洛克  你吓死我了
Sherloque, you scared me to death.
我的错
Well, I apologize.
但是你不回我的表情包的时候
But when you don't answer my many emoticon pictograms,
不  我担心死你了
no, I fear the worst, huh?
我那时在图书馆  能有什么事
I was in the library. What could've happened to me?
书架坍塌  暴怒的图书管理员
Stacks collapse. Livid librarian.
-你认真的吗  - 死于杜威图书十进制分类法
- Really? - Death by Dewey Decimals?
因为延期还书费死人
Yeah, life lost by late fees?
-你很上道  -当然
- Ha-ha! There you go. - Yeah. Oh.
我们走吧
Shall we?
抱歉  我当时没看信息
I'm sorry I didn't-- I didn't check my texts.
我的意思是  我一整天都没看手机了
I mean, well, actually I haven't checked my phone all day, so...
然而一个人平均每天查看110次手机
And yet the average person checks their phone 110 times a day.
-这不是真的  -这是真的  不信你查
- That's not true. - That is true. Look it up.
还有图书馆就在实验中心旁边
Well, also the library's right next to the tech lab.
所以我的信号特别差
So, you know, I get terrible reception in there.
然而就在不到一英里外建了一座信号塔
And yet that built a cell phone tower less than a mile away.
也没有什么区别
Hasn't made a difference.
我不知道  或许只是我的手机太烂了
I don't know, Maybe my phone's just crap.
或者你不想回复
Or maybe you don't want to respond
因为回复了就会讨论到你的秘密
because then you would have to discuss your secret.
-我的秘密  -是的你的秘密
- My secret? - Yes, your secret.
遇险广播
跑  快跑
Run. Run!
什么
What?
是歇洛克  蝉在中城大学
It's Sherloque. Cicada's at CCU.
在吉特咖啡屋的时候  你开门没用手
So at Jitters, I saw you open the door without touching it.
我知道你有超能力  是什么超能力
I know you have powers. What are they?
这个
That.
我也看到你了
I see you too.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我觉得还好
I think so.
诺拉
Nora.
你找到什么了吗
Hey, you find anything?
我们确认了蝉女没偷到她想要的所有东西
Confirmation that She-cada hasn't stolen everything she needs.
所以我们还有一点时间
So we have some time.
终于有些好消息了
Finally some good news.
她偷到的是量子隧道转换器
Except what she did steal was a Quantum Tunnel Converter.
第一个可以工作的原型
The first working prototype of its kind.
西斯科第一次听到的时候也是这个表情
Yeah, that's the same face Cisco made when he heard.
那个转化器可以将暗物质能量转化成实际能量
The converter can transform dark matter energy to practical energy.
蝉要用她的匕首去充能雾化器
Cicada's gonna use her dagger to superpower the atomizer.
如果她想将它连接雾化器
If she wants to connect it to the atomizer,
她所需要的最后一部分是超导管
the last piece she'll need is a hyper-conduit,
至少那个东西挺难找到
and those are pretty hard to come by, to say the least.
如果她能在中城区附近找到一个
She'll be lucky to locate one in the CC area at all.
我们最好比她先找到
Well, we better find it first.
我们这就去找
We'll get to it.
慢点喝
Small sips, huh?
她看到我的那一刻  就想要我死
The second she saw me, she wanted me dead.
她试图杀了我  歇洛克
She tried to kill me, Sherloque.
因为你的超能力
Because of what you are.
一个磁力超能力者
A magnokinetic meta-human!
你的超能力  有两下子
That was something, your powers, huh?
我想要告诉你  但是
I wanted to tell you, but...
我不知道你会怎么想
I didn't know what you'd think.
我觉得
I think...
你是最棒的
the world of you.
任何事情都不能改变这个事实
Nothing is ever going to change that.
你觉得蝉还会回来找我吗
Do you think Cicada's gonna come back again to try to find me?
再试着杀掉我
To try again?
是的  我觉得她不会停下来
Yes. I don't think she'll stop.
我该怎么办
What am I gonna do?
你猜怎么着
Well, you know what?
我觉得我可以帮助你
I believe I can help you with that.
你们两个还好吗
Guys, you okay?
还好  我需要告诉你一些事情
Yeah, uh, I need to tell you something.
就在我们往这里跑的时候
When we were running over here,
我又一次与格蕾丝心灵感应了
I connected to Grace's mind again.
我能看到她的视角
I could see through her eyes.
等一下  就像那次
Wait, like the same thing you did
蝉攻击爱丽丝·博兰生日派对那样
when Cicada attacked Alice Bolan's birthday party?
是啊  我们肯定还是心灵相通的
Yeah, we must still be psychically connected
从我那次进入了格蕾丝的脑中之后
from when I was in Grace's mindscape.
这就是导致红色闪电的原因
That's what caused the red lightning.
你感受到的愤怒  不是你的
The anger that you felt, it wasn't yours.
是她的
It was hers.
我们可以利用这点
We can use this.
假设我可以看到她哪怕只有一秒
If I can see where she is just for a second,
我们就可以向她那里跑
we can run to her.
这可能就是阻止二代蝉的关键
Guy, this is the key to stopping Cicada II.
不行
No.
不行  诺拉  这样太危险了
No, Nora, it's too dangerous.
-我们还不知道有什么副作用  -不知道
- We don't even know what the side effects are. - No.
我们刚把这些从你身体里除掉
We just got the stuff out of you.
我们不会再让你去冒险了
We're not risking exposing you to that again.
妈妈  我想要这么做
Mom, I want to do this.
我们会找到另一种办法的
We'll find another way.
眩晕感过一阵就会消退
The dizziness should subside shortly.
保证他得到足够的休息
Make sure he gets lots of rest.
我们知道你感到焦虑
Hey, we know you're feeling anxious.
但是我保证你现在安全了
But I promise you're safe now.
在那边出去
Head out that way.
我去看看还有没有别人
I'm gonna go see if there's anyone else.
我们要重启蝉的举报热线吗
Should we reopen the Cicada tip line?
杜普雷问你要在哪开安全检查点
And Dupree's asking where you want the security checkpoints.
好的
Uh, yeah.
对  开检查点  应该开在
Uh, yes. Open it and, uh, checkpoints should be
中城警局两边以外的两个街区
two blocks on either side of the CCPD. Okay?
事实上  三  三个街区吧
Uh, actually, three--three blocks.
你还好吗
Hey, you. You good?
是的  我还好  快看
Yeah, yeah. I'm good. Look.
他们又在播出爱瑞丝的故事了
They are airing Iris' story again.
超能力者连环杀手蝉的最新消息
New updates on the meta-human serial killer Cicada,
中城大学袭击促使超能力解药免费
最近刚刚袭击了中城大学
who recently attacked Central City University.
对这些袭击作出回应
Now in response to these attacks,
中城的市民反应说中城警局
The Central City Citizen reports that CCPD,
与尖端科研实验室合作
in conjunction with S.T.A.R. Labs,
正在对外提供一种开创性的超能力解药
is offering a groundbreaking meta-human cure,
完全免费
entirely free of cost.
或许我应该叫晚班的人来的早一点
Maybe I should call the night shift in earlier.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
或者不叫
Or not.
乔  我刚刚感觉到了一股恐慌
Joe, I just felt a huge wave of panic.
我们马上要人满为患了
We're about to get slammed in here.
所有人  请耐心等待  我们会轮到你
Everyone, please be patient. We'll get to you.
这么远足够了
Far enough.
好吧
Okay.
斯塔格工业  水星实验室  伊沃实验室
Stagg, Mercury, Ivo.
没有一个地方的超导管
None of them have a hyper-conduit compatible
与蝉偷的转换器兼容
with the converter Cicada stole.
现在我确实经历过一次
You know, now that I've actually experienced
时空穿越
this whole time travel thing,
我觉得我比以前更了解一点了
I think I understand it a little bit better.
这让我越来越不明白斯旺的计划
Which makes me understand Thawne's plan less and less.
他为什么把诺拉送回来创造一个新的蝉
Why would he send Nora back to create a new Cicada
只为了让一个更新的蝉出现
only for a newer Cicada to appear
比诺拉创造的蝉更难阻止
who's harder to stop than the one Nora created?
拉尔夫  我们能不能不要想斯旺的计划
Ralph, can we get away from Thawne's plan
来想想我们的计划是什么
and try to stick to our own?
好的  我  我只是
Yeah, yeah, I--I just--
我觉得在这些乱七八糟的时空穿越里
I feel like there might be an answer
有一个能帮助我们解答这些问题的答案
in this timey-wimey crap that could help us solve this.
诺拉  在2049年你会到哪里找这个超导管
Nora, where would you find this hyper-conduit in 2049?
大概在欧林实验室吧
Probably Ollins Laboratory.
欧林在量子工程领域得了诺贝尔奖
Ollins won a Nobel Prize for quantum engineering.
欧林  你是在说塞巴斯蒂安·欧林
Ollins? As in Sebastian Ollins?
是啊  你认识他
Yeah, do you know him?
他是一个真正的天才
He's a true genius.
你说他是天才
A genius, you say.
一个在物理课上根本睁不开眼睛的人
The guy couldn't even stay awake through a single physics lecture.
事实上  我很确定如果不是他非常聪明
In fact, I'm pretty sure if it wasn't for his very smart,
非常体贴的大学室友
very considerate college roommate
借给他笔记看  帮助他学习
lending him notes, helping him study,
他根本考不过期末考试
he wouldn't have made it through his finals!
诺贝尔奖个鬼
Nobel Prize my ass!
是的  他认识他
Yeah, he knows him.
你知道吗  这根本不重要
You know what? It doesn't even matter.
人生太短  不值得花费我的生命
Life's too short and I'm not about to spend my life
去担心小塞巴斯蒂安·欧林
worrying about little Sebastian Ollins.
找到他了
Found him.
看起来他租了一个仓库
Looks like he's been renting a warehouse
在南面的某个地方
somewhere on the Southside
然后他把那个仓库用纤维焦耳科技改装
and then he retrofitted it with fiber-joules technology
去给他的实验做测试
to test out his experiments.
包含一个高端科技的导管
Including one bleeding-edge hyper-conduit.
我去抢在格蕾丝之前拿回来
I'll go get it before Grace can.
-我跟着你  -我...
- Right behind you. - I, um...
我觉得这次你别来了
I--I think you should sit this one out.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
诺拉  你和格蕾丝之间的关联
Nora, your connection with Grace.
让你太冒风险了
It puts you in too much danger.
我们不了解  我觉得你最好
I mean, we don't-I think it's best for you
还是别出去了  等我们阻止她再说
to just stay out of the field until we stop her.
那所以呢  我现在没法帮队伍了吗
So what? Now I can't help the team at all?
诺拉  请你理解下
Nora, please understand.
你在这里要安全多了
Look, you would be much safer here.
好了  我到了
All right, I'm here.
没看到蝉
No sign of Cicada.
很好  拿上导管就走吧
Great. Grab the conduit and get out of there.
我想我找到了些什么
I think I got something.
巴里
Barry!
她已经拿到导管了
She's already got the conduit.
她还炸掉了欧林的仓库
And she blew up Ollins' warehouse.
格蕾丝需要的东西都齐了
Grace has everything she needs.
和我们想的一样
It's just like we thought.
这下好
Great.
什么
What?
有了她偷走的这些零件
With all the pieces that she's stolen,
格蕾丝现在可以用她那匕首给
Grace can now use the dagger's dark matter energy
雾化器充暗物质了
to supercharge the atomizer.
显然只杀死中城的超能力者
Apparently it wasn't enough for her
对她来说还不够
to just kill all the metas in Central City.
有了这个超级充电器
With this super-charge,
她能杀死整个国家的超能力者
she'll kill every meta in the country.
好了  看着
All right, look,
我知道你们想让我别管斯旺那事
I know you guys want me off this whole Thawne thing,
-但你们得看看这个  -拉尔夫
- but you've got to hear this. - Ralph.
不  你们得看看这个
No, you've got to look at this.
你们得听听
You've got to hear this.
给我一小会的时间  好吗
So just--just give me a second, all right?
-好吧  -求你了
- All right. - Please.
那么  这个是原先的时间线
All right, so, this is the original timeline
有原始的蝉  大卫·赫希
with the original Cicada, David Hersch.
这是大悟之道那晚
This is the night of the Enlightenment,
诺拉帮手卫星之后
when Nora interfered with the satellite,
就有了我们的蝉  奥林·德怀尔
giving us our Cicada, Orlin Dwyer.
这也是格蕾丝陷入昏迷的那晚
That's also the same night that Grace goes into a coma.
这里开始就变得复杂了
This is where it gets complicated.
在未来的某个时刻
At some point in the future,
格蕾丝醒来  成为了一个全新的蝉
Grace wakes up, she becomes her own full-fledged Cicada.
她穿越回来
She goes back in time,
用她自己的匕首杀死了叔叔
she kills her Uncle with his own dagger.
那德怀尔杀的那些超能力者呢
What happens to all the metas that Dwyer killed?
他们变成没被杀了吗
Do they get un-killed?
那格蕾丝在未来杀的那些超能力者呢
What about all the metas that Grace killed in the future?
她是用什么杀掉的
What did she kill them with?
还有最重要的
And most importantly,
格蕾丝没有杀死德怀尔的那条时间线呢
what happens in the timeline where Grace never killed Dwyer.
这里边对不上
Something doesn't add up.
你或许是对的
You might be right.
但现在  我们要是不处理掉那个匕首
But right now, there won't be any future for any metas
超能力者就不会有未来
if we don't get rid of that dagger.
现在  这是我们的最后机会
Now. This is our last chance.
咱们得想办法找到格蕾丝
We have to figure out how to find Grace.
不然我们会失去所有人
Or we lose everyone.
我们去看看卫星能找到什么
We'll go see what the satellites can do.
也许我们能遇到奇迹
Maybe we're due for a miracle.
二代蝉
来吧
Hey, come on.
你觉得我们的决定是正确的吗
Do you think we made the right decision
不让诺拉参加行动
leaving Nora out of this?
我是说  她回来的原因
I mean, the whole reason she came back
本就是要与蝉战斗
was to fight Cicada in the first place.
我们是她的家长  好吗
We're her parents, all right?
我们的工作就是保护她不受伤害
It's our job to protect her from harm.
这么做的最好方法就是让她远离
The best way to do that is just to keep her far away from it.
你对凯特琳和冰霜杀手的关联有效果
You worked for Caitlin and Killer Frost's connection.
现在看看你能对我和格蕾丝起什么作用吧
Let's see what you can do for me and Grace.
怎么花了这么久
What's taking so long?
你还剩下多少解药
Look, how much more cure do you have left?
听着  我们还有很多
Listen, we have plenty.
请耐心  我们会尽快
Please, uh, we will administer the cure
分发解药给大家  好吗
as fast as we can, people. Okay?
韦斯特警探  我们需要额外人手来控制人群
Detective West, we need additional squads to aid the crowd control.
好  带两人过去
Uh, yeah, take--take two.
不不  带三个  两个  两个
No--no, no. Take three. Two, two, two.
乔  我们需要更多的酒精棉签
Joe, we need more alcohol swabs.
宝贝  你没事吧
Babe, you okay?
好呀  好呀
Hey, oh! Hey, oh!
-歇洛克  -这是凯瑟琳·斯诺博士
- Sherloque? - So, Dr. Caitlin Snow.
这是塞西尔·霍尔顿和乔·韦斯特警探
This is Cecile Horton and Detective Joe West.
这是我的
This is my...
这是瑞内·艾德勒小姐
this is Mademoiselle Renée Adler.
-你好  是艾德勒  -艾德勒  还有瑞内
- Hi. Adler. - Adler. And Renée,
这些人可以帮助你
these are the people that can help you.
所以你真的可以移除我的超能力吗
So you can actually just remove my powers?
你想要我们就可以
We can if you want us to.
那是永久的吗
And--and this would be permanent?
是永久的  没错
Oh, it's permanent, yes.
但是比蝉永久杀死你好多了
But better than Cicada permanently killing you.
对吗  跟她说说  警探
Am I right? Tell her detective.
-没错吧  -是的
- That's right? Right? - Yes.
你感觉到很紧张  我能看出来
Uh, you're feeling nervous, I can tell.
但是蝉是真的想要
But Cicada really is trying to kill
杀死这城市里所有的超能力者
every meta-human in this city.
你要干什么
Hey, what's your problem?
后退  我站在这里呢
Back off! I'm standing here.
你的眼睛有问题吗
Is something wrong with your eyes?
没问题
They're fine.
那就别挡我道
Then get out of my way.
好了  好了  散开
All right, all right. Break it up.
我们得快点了
We need to keep this line moving.
要关押他们吗  警探
Want us to detain them, Detective?
给我解药我就走人
Just give me the cure and I'll get out of here.
不行  我先来的  你知道的
No way! I was here first! You know that!
长官  我们要怎么办
Sir, what should we do?
警探  我们只剩下一个小队了
Detective, we've got one squad left.
给我解药我就走人了
Give me the cure and I'll get out of here.
够了
Enough!
给我点时间考虑
I need a minute to think.
我真是...
I'm so--
瑞内
Renée?
她在那里啊
There she is.
是西塞尔
That was Cecile.
中城警局聚集了一堆恐慌的人群
CCPD is flooded with a lot of really scared people.
有任何格蕾丝的暗物质信号吗
Are there any signs of Grace's dark matter signature?
没有  什么都没有  甚至连...
No. Nothing. Not even a--
是她吗
Is that her?
诺拉
Nora!
巴里  她听不到你
Barry, she can't hear you.
我觉得她也看不到我们
I don't think she can see us either.
诺拉  诺拉
Nora! Nora!
诺拉
Nora!
你在想什么
What were you thinking?
诺拉  你差点让自己得脑动脉瘤
Nora, you almost gave yourself an aneurysm.
我想找到格蕾丝
I was tring to find Grace.
让你自己向格蕾丝和她的愤怒开放
Opening yourself up to Grace and her rage
也会让你向负神速力开放
also opens you up to the Negative Speed Force.
我们不想发生这种事
We don't know anything about it.
你不明白这有多危险吗
Don't you get how dangerous that is?
是的  我知道
Yeah, I do.
我还是想试试  我必须试试
And I still wanna try. I have to try.
诺拉  你的试试差点毁了西斯科的工作室
Nora, you tring almost destroyed Cisco's workshop
还差点弄死你自己
and almost got yourself killed.
更别提  如果蝉通过你眼睛看到东西怎么办
Not to mention, what if Cicada saw through your eyes?
你可能会暴露我们的位置
You could've given away our location.
不  我确保了视线里没有任何
No, I made sure there was nothing in my eye line
能联系到尖端科研实验室的东西
that said S.T.A.R. Labs.
听我说
Guys, listen.
我看到了格蕾丝  差点看到她在哪里
I saw Grace and I almost saw where she was.
现在她正在进行组装
Right now she is putting her pieces together
一旦完成
and when that is done,
不是数千就是数十万人
thousands if not hundreds of thousands of people
会死去
are going to die.
我不能坐视不管
I can't stand around and do nothing.
你可以不管  这是我们要求的
Yes, you can because that's what we're telling you to do.
我刚来这里时  我做事很仓促
When I first got here, I would rush in to fix things
这样下来我经常把事情搞得更糟
and by doing that, I always ended up making them worse.
但我不再是那个人了
But I am not that person anymore
因为你
because of you.
你教会了我怎样使用我的超能力
You showed me how to use my powers.
你教会了我怎样做出正确选择
You taught me how to make the right choices.
现在  我选择面对风险
And right now, I am choosing to face this risk.
诺拉  这是个糟糕的主意
Nora, this is a terrible idea.
我知道你们这样想
I know you feel that way.
但我不
But I don't.
我是个成年人  可以自己做决定
I'm an adult capable of making my own decisions.
我已经决定了
I've made up my mind about this.
所以我求你们  拜托  作为我的父母
So I am asking you, please, as my parents,
不要再试图让我远离危险
stop trying to keep me away from this danger
帮我去面对它
and start helping me face it.
不  不用担心  我可以解决
No, no, no, no, no. Don't worry. I can handle it.
好的
All right.
你在做什么  那些人不知所措
What are you doing? Those people are overwhelmed.
他们不知道做什么
They don't know what to do.
他们需要你  而你走开了
They need you and you just-- you walked away?
抱歉  我不是故意的  我只是...
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to. It's just--
你刚才是不是在和辛格通话
Okay, did I just catch you on the phone with Singh
想知道他能多快赶回来
trying to find out how fast he was gonna be back?
塞西尔  我不适合掌管
Cecil, I--I--I'm not used to being in charge
这些管理和后勤的东西
of all this managerial and logistic stuff.
-我不是这块料  -你说的什么话
- I'm just not cut out for that. - What are you talking about?
宝贝  我看到过你在外勤
Babe, I have seen you take charge
掌管大局千万次了
in the field a million times.
但这不是外勤
But that's in the field
我一向知道如果这方面出了问题
and I always knew that I had Singh to go to
我可以找辛格帮忙
if I had any problems this way.
现在所有人都找我帮忙
Now everybody's coming to me
我无法回答所有问题
and I can't answer all these questions.
乔·韦斯特
Joe West.
有多少次巴里  爱瑞丝  诺拉
How many times has Barry, Iris, Nora,
甚至拉尔夫·德比来找你
even Ralph Dibny come to you?
专门来找你来解决他们的问题
Specifically come to you to get answers to their problems?
数不过来
More times than I can count.
正是
Exactly.
正是因为他们知道
And that is because everyone of them knows
当他们找你
that when they come to you,
他们会得到发自内心的
they're gonna get an honest answer
真诚回答
straight from the heart.
宝贝  你的内心是道德罗盘
Babe, that heart of yours, that is a moral compass.
这是我爱你的众多原因之一
It's one of the many reasons why I love you.
这里
Right here.
这是全部你需要的  宝贝  这里
That's all you need, babe. Right here.
只要是你的肺腑之言
As long as you speak from there,
我保证  你永远不会把任何人引入歧途
I promise you, you will never lead anyone astray.
-歇洛克  -是我
- Sherloque. - Yes.
歇洛克  对不起我跑了
Sherloque, I'm sorry I ran.
我只是感到不知所措
I was--. Just feeling so overwhelmed.
我只是想让你感到安全
All I wanted to do... make you feel safe.
但我让你感到
And then I put you in a position where you
不知所措和不安
feel overwhelmed and not safe.
听着  我们去尖端科研实验室  安静又安全
But look, we'll go to S.T.A.R. Labs, quiet and safe.
我们进行治疗  没问题的
We'll administer the cure. It will be great.
歇洛克  那不是...
Look, Sherloque, that's--.
那不是我跑的原因
That's not why I ran away.
-不是吗  -不是
- It's not? - No.
我不想用解药
I don't wanna take the cure.
-你不想  -不想
- You don't? - No.
我喜欢我的超能力
I love having my powers.
是吗
You do?
是的
Y--yes and yes,
知道有个杀手在针对我这类人
is it scary knowing that there's a killer out there
是挺可怕的  但是...
that's targeting people like me, but...
我不想改变我自己
I don't want to change who I am.
我不想因为恐惧屈服
I don't want to give into fear
只是因为有危险
just because there's danger involved.
你知道吗
You know?
我想过我自己想要的生活
I want to live my life on my terms.
作为超能力者
As a meta-human.
你很勇敢
No, but you're brave.
我只是担心蝉不会停止
I just worry that Cicada won't stop
直到她杀光所有超能力者
until she kills every meta-human on this...
这个地球上的
On this earth.
有个办法
There is a way.
让你依然拥有超能力  并且远离蝉
For you to still have your powers and be free of Cicada.
-怎么办  -去别的地球
- How? - On a different Earth,
那里你会很安全
where'd you be safe.
在你作为图书管理员的职业生涯中
In your travels in your career as a librarian,
你有没有听过多重宇宙理论
have you ever heard of the theory of the "Multi-verse"?
所以这是个打开去另一个世界
So--so this a device that opens
-传送门的装置  -是的
- a portal to another world. - Yes.
-是的  -我选择世界吗
- Right. - Any world I choose?
你好聪明  你很快跟上了
Right. You're so smart. You catch on so quickly.
有些人就是不相信
You know, some people, they just don't believe.
几周前我在六点新闻看到一个巨型鲨鱼
Well, a few weeks ago I saw a giant shark
和一个巨型猩猩打架
fighting a giant gorilla on the 6:00 news, so...
说的没错
That's a good point.
听着  我要送你去的地球
Now look, this Earth that I'm going to send you to,
是我的地球
it's...it's my Earth.
我有几个朋友在那边等你
I'll have some friends there to meet you,
但要保密
but secret, huh?
这趟旅行不能告诉任何人
This trip, you must not tell anyone
因为一旦蝉发现有多个地球
because if Cicada were to find out there's multiple Earths
这些地球上有超能力者
and each one of these Earths contains meta-humans,
他们会成为她的下一个目标
no, they would be her next target. Hmm?
-怎么  -跟我来
- What? - Come with me.
我必须留下来
No, I must stay.
现在知道了蝉是这个地球的威胁
Now knowing Cicada is a threat to this Earth,
我必须和我的朋友们一同战斗
I must fight alongside my friends.
闪电侠小队  他们就像是...
You know, Team Flash, they're like...
他们就像是我的家人  当这一切结束了
They're like a family to me but when I am done...
我会去找你
I will come find you.
你就是我一直在等的那个女人
You are the woman I have been waiting for.
所以
So...
我知道
I know.
-准备好了吗  -好了
- Okay, you ready? - Yeah.
好的
All right.
快
Allez.
你说得对
You were right.
我们教会了你怎样成为一个英雄
We taught you how to be a hero.
所以当你表现得像个英雄时我们不该生气
So we shouldn't be angry at you when you act like one.
我知道你们只是担心我会受伤
I know you're just afraid I'll get hurt.
总是会有危险
There's always going to be danger
要你去面对  诺拉
that you're going to face, Nora.
我们不能一直牵着你的手
And we can't hold your hand through all of it.
尽管我们很想
As much as we want to.
你是我们的女儿  但你不是个孩子了
You're our daughter but you're not a kid.
你说得对  你有能力做自己的决定
You're right, you are capable of making your own decisions.
你真的觉得你可以控制你和
You really think you can control your connection
负神速力的联系  找到格蕾丝
to the Negative Speed Force, find Grace for us?
是的  我可以
Yeah, I do.
我只要你们在我这么做的时候保证我们家的安全
All I need is for you guys to keep our home safe while I do it.
我想我知道怎么做
I think I know how.
我们找到蝉
Let's find Cicada.
这东西真能勾起人的回忆
Man, this thing brings back memories.
-好的还是坏的  -斯旺的
- Good ones? Bad ones? - Thawne ones.
我们将逆闪电困在里边过
We trapped the Reverse-Flash in this thing
那时还不知道他是斯旺
before we even knew he was Thawne.
结果我们只是困住了极速幻象
But we actually ended up trapping his Speed Mirage.
而他本人却坐在轮椅里休息
while his real self just sat there chilling in his wheelchair.
天啊  斯旺的计中计
Man, Thawne's plans got plans.
不用害怕  信徒们
But fear not, true believers.
斯旺陷阱2.0更小  更时尚  更强
The Thawne Trap 2.0 is smaller, sleeker, and stronger.
我已经把曲折点加强了
I've gone ahead and sharpened the inflexion points
以便适应你的负神速力能量
to account for your Negative Speed Force energy.
所以即使你在里边像《天崩地裂》那样闹
So if you go full "Dante's Peak" in there,
我们在这边也会很安全
we'll be safe out here.
这也意味着即使你需要我  我也无法穿进去
It also means I can't phase in there if you need me.
你爸爸和我会一直在这里
Your dad and I will be right here the whole time.
你们一直都在
You always are.
你能做到的
You got this.
我们去抓住这个大坏蛋吧
Let's go catch our big bad.
打扰一下  打扰一下
Excuse me! Excuse me!
各位  请安静
People, please! Please!
谢谢
Thank you.
从未见过面的各位  我是乔·韦斯特警探
For all of you I haven't met, I'm Detective Joe West.
我不是超能力者  我不知道那是什么感觉
Now I am not a meta-human. I don't know what that's like.
但是我知道害怕和不知所措是什么感受
But I do know what it's like to be afraid and overwhelmed.
你们来到这里是想要答案
You all came here because you wanted answers
而且你们需要帮助
and you needed help.
我本人以及中城警局的所有人
Myself and everybody else here at CCPD
会在这里帮助你们
are here to help you.
我发誓
So I swear to you,
双方都再多一点耐心
with a little bit of patience from all of us,
我们会一起克服困难
we will get through this together.
谢谢
Thank you.
警官们  我们继续
Officers, let's start moving the line again.
我们会照顾到所有人的
We're gonna get to everybody.
准备好
Hold onto your butts.
她们连接上了
They're connected.
我能看到完整的雾化器
I can see the completed atomizer.
但我不知道她要带去哪里
But I can't see where she's taking it.
记住  诺拉  你感受到的不是你的愤怒
Remember Nora, that's not your anger.
是她的
It's hers.
诺拉
Nora.
我知道你在做什么
I see what you're doing.
有什么把她激怒了
Okay, something pissed her off.
是你的记忆机器让你回到了我的脑子里吗
Is your memory machine letting you back into my head?
不
No.
是我自己要来
This is all me.
我不能让你释放病毒  格蕾丝
I can't let you release that virus, Grace.
成千上万的人会死
Thousands will die.
今天会死成千上万的人  明天会更多
Thousands today. Even more tomorrow.
我醒来的那个世界
The world I wake up in
被拥有超能力的人占领
is overrun with people with impossible powers.
他们杀死无辜的人
Destroying innocent lives.
使家庭变得支离破碎  就像我的家庭那样
Ripping families apart. Just like mine was.
这一切都是因为你们
And all of this is because of you!
这很糟糕吗
Is that bad?
很不好  我要把她拉出来
Well, it's not good. I'm pulling her out.
不  不要  她会控制住的
No, no. No, she'll get control.
你的闪电家族创造了超能力者
Your Flash family created meta-humans.
粒子加速器  公车超能力者
The Particle Accelerator. The bus metas.
你们击碎的大悟之道卫星
The Enlightenment satellite which you shattered!
这不是我的愤怒
This isn't my anger.
是你的
It's yours.
也许你看起来不一样了  格蕾丝
You may look different, Grace.
但你仍然是我第一次来这里时看到的
But you're still the angry little girl I met
那个愤怒的小女孩
the first time I came here.
我很抱歉你要承受这种愤怒
I'm sorry you have to carry that anger.
但是你要一个人承受它
But you're gonna have to carry it alone
因为我做出了自己的决定
because I make my own decisions,
我决定不能变得像你一样
and I've decided not to be like you.
中城警局
诺拉
Nora!
她在中城警局
She's-- she's at CCPD.
立刻把所有人都带出去
Get everybody out of here right now!
-塞西尔  快走  -快跑  快跑
- Cecil, go. Go! - Move, move, move!
现在他们的末日开始了
And now their end begins.
蝉在中城警局  但是她可能在任何地方
Cicada's at CCPD but she could use the atomizer
用雾化器散播病毒
to spread the virus from anywhere.
那里有几百个超能力者
There are hundreds of metas there.
她会试图杀死他们所有人
She's going to try and take all of their lives.
不是杀死他们  是为了他们的暗物质
Not their lives, their dark matter.
她要把所有的超能力者当成电池
She's going to use all those metas like a battery.
我们要怎么做
What are we gonna do?
我们过去  失去超能力  毁掉匕首
Reach in, lose our powers, destroy the dagger,
阻止蝉像超女一样飞走
stop Cicada from Supergirl-ing away,
然后重整应对情感创伤的副作用[辐射]
then regroup for the emotional fallout.
辐射  西斯科  辐射核爆炸时
Fallout. Cisco, where did you send Fallout's energy
你把他的能量送到哪里了
when he was going nuclear?
地球十五  是一颗死星
Earth-15. It's a dead Earth.
我们把雾化器传送到那里
Let's breach the atomizer there.
-我和你们一起去  -诺拉  听着
- I'm coming with you! - Nora, look.
你已经帮忙了  你做得足够多了  好吗
You've already helped. More than enough, all right?
好吧  帮我个忙
Okay, just do me a favor.
把那把匕首炸碎
Blast that dagger to hell.
我一定会的
Absolutely.
滚出我的警局
Get out of my precinct.
板球怪人
Hey, Cricket freak.
你和我还有没处理完的事
You and I have some unfinished business.
-打得好  -不会让她昏迷太久
- Nice hit. - It won't keep her down long.
我们为什么还有超能力  我们已经赢了吗
Why do we have our powers? Did we already win?
还没有  匕首插在雾化器里
Not yet. The dagger's in the atomizer.
等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait!
如果匕首还插在里面时我们就击中它
If we shoot the dagger while it's still in there,
可能会引爆病毒
it could detonate the virus.
各位  她要醒了
Guys, she's waking up.
好吧  找出让它停止的办法
All right, figure out a way to stop it.
-我会拖住她  -好
- I'll keep her off your back. - All right.
这个会有点帮助
This will help.
西斯科  拔出匕首然后把雾化器传送走
Cisco, remove the dagger and then breach the atomizer away.
有一个小问题
Yeah, there's a slight problem there.
把这个东西传送到任何地方都有可能会引爆
Breaching this thing anywhere could set it off.
我的超能力在这里没有用
My powers are useless here.
那就用你的另一个超能力  你的头脑
Then use your other power. Your mind.
调出雾化器的蓝图
Bring up the atomizer blueprints.
我会用科技解决你
I'm gonna have to science the crap out of you.
早安  阳光甜心
Good morning, sunshine.
没有能力抑制匕首  情况不一样了吧
A little different without your power-dampening dagger, huh?
我不用匕首也能杀死你
Oh, I don't need a dagger to kill you.
我来到这个时间之前从来没用过匕首
I never had it before I came to this time.
你想杀死我吗  那就过来吧
You wanna kill me? Come get me.
我也一样
What she said.
移开金属板之后
Once you remove the plate,
你应该会看到控制处理器面板
you should be able to see the control processor plane.
我看到了  没有用
I see it. It's not gonna work.
我需要一台量子计算机才能黑进这个东西
I need a quantum computer to hack this thing.
等等  我有
Wait! I have one.
对
Yeah.
你的护手
Your gauntlet!
我爱未来
Damn, I love the future.
如果我能从里面连接这三个节点
Okay, if I can connect to the three nodes inside,
我就可以重写系统
I'll override the system.
如果我碰到其它东西
If I touch anything else,
那就再见了
hasta la vista, baby.
好了
Okay.
我成功了
There. I got it.
很好  搞定另两个需要多久
Yeah, great. Um, how long for the other two?
这要看我们还剩多少时间
However long we have left.
搞定两个了
Two down.
你动手操作的能力不怎么样啊
Well, you're not great at the Operation game, are you?
你的建设性批评提得很糟糕
You suck at constructive criticism!
西斯科  快离开那里
Cisco, get out of there.
马上就好
Almost there.
进去了
It's in.
糟糕
Oh, shrap.
西斯科  怎么了
Cisco, what's going on?
太晚了
It's too late.
成功了
Gotcha.
-雾化器关掉了  -闪电侠
- The Atomizer's off. - Flash!
匕首
The dagger.
第二代蝉
如果有什么能够摧毁那把匕首的话
Anything's gonna destroy that dagger,
就是这支镜像枪
it's gonna be the mirror gun.
这里边对不上
Something doesn't add up.
计中计
Plans got plans.
她在未来没有匕首
She didn't have the dagger in the future.
匕首就是斯旺的计划
The dagger is Thawne's plan.
别开枪
Don't shoot it.